ANIESH CHAWLA

Phone :+1 (312) 520-0435 · email: chawla.niesh@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/anieshchawla/

A leader and an excellent team player with more than 7+ years of experience in computer science and data analysis. Have a broad experience in software development life cycle and spearheading engineering processes in startup leading to business growth and development

EDUCATION		
PURDUE UNIVERSITY, WEST LAFAYETTE, IN		
Master of Science in Computer Engineering	3.9/4.0	2017 - 2019
INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (IIT), DELHI		
Masters of Technology in Information and Comm. Tech	8.5/10	2006 - 2011

INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (IIT), DELHI

Bachelors of Technology in Electrical Engineering 7.9/10 2006 - 2011

EXPERIENCE

GOOGLE INC, NC Durham, NC

Software Engineer (July 2019 – Present)

[Golang, Typescript, Java, Javascript]

- Created and Implemented multiple engineering design and architecture of various backend services to create new product launches and improve the efficiency of the overall systems.
- Designed and developed backend services to increase the privacy transparency of Google products.
- Proactively implemented a new process to consolidate comments in a single view for ease of access that led to an increase in product excellence and customer satisfaction by 10%.

TESLA MOTORS, CA Fremont, CA

Summer Internship (May 2018 – July 2018)

[Python, Kafka]

- Architected and implemented software to automate Tesla car firmware validation to emulate the production line
- Automated report generation through SQL and Python for firmware testing on production line for Model S/X
- Solutions led to reduction of 100+ man hours per week which led to savings of ~\$20K/month

SANCTUM NETWORKS, INDIA

Bangalore, India

Product Engineer (March 2015 - April 2017)

[C/C++, Python, Storm, Kafka, Zookeeper, Mongo]

- Architected software solution for collecting, analyzing & interpreting network data for Liberty Global
- 100 times scaled up performance by introducing Apache Storm and Kafka architecture in software codebase
- Led a team of 5 people to enable SDN based Wi-Fi/IoT orchestration at SOHO by leveraging Netconf

INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (IIT), DELHI

Delhi, India

Project scientist(March 2014 - March 2015)

[C/C++]

Modified the TCP protocol to reduce latency in Wi-Fi services. This led to increased performance of TCP by 20%. The results were verified by testing on both NS3 simulations and Linux machine

AMERICAN EXPRESS

Gurgaon, India

Business Analyst (March 2012 – March 2014)

[Hadoop, SQL, SAS]

Spearheaded Big Data initiative in Fraud Strategy by integrating new capabilities like Sequence Mining, Random Forest, K- nearest neighbor specifically for proactive detection of fraud at POS. Awarded Analyst of the Quarter

ACADEMIC PROJECTS & EMPLOYMENT

Master's Project

West Lafayette, IN

Reliability of Network Cameras, Purdue(Jan 2018 - Present)

[scikit-learn, PyTorch, Python]

- Architected the solution for identifying parameters for finding useful cameras during emergency responses
- Built Neural Networks and leveraged Computer Vision algorithms to identify such useful cameras

RELATED COURSEWORK

Data Mining, Linear Algebra, Random Variables, Graph Theory, Data Structures, Algorithms, Convex Optimization, OS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient in Java, C/C++, Python, PyTourch, SQL, Erlang, MySQL, MongoDB, Apache Storm, Kafka, Elastic Search

PUBLICATIONS

- C. Surakitbanharn, C. Yau, G. Wang, A. Chawla, Y. Pan, Z. Sun, S. Yellin, D. Ebert, Y. Lu, G. Thiruvathukal "Cross-referencing social media and public surveillance camera data for disaster response", 2018 IEEE International Conference on Technologies for Homeland Security (HST), Waltham, MA, 2011
- Singh, D.; Singh, V.; Chawla, A.; Pangtey, S.; Ribeiro, V., "UDA: Fast Transport Protocol for D2D Networks over WiFi" poster, Communication Systems and Networks (COMSNETS), 2017 9th International Conference, 3-7 Jan. 2017
- Chawla, A; Yadav, V.; Dev Sharma, V.; Bajaj, J.; Nanda, E.; Ribeiro, V.; Saran, H., "RODEO: Robust and rapidly deployable TDM mesh with QoS differentiation," Communication Systems and Networks (COMSNETS), 2012 Fourth International Conference, vol., no., pp.1,6, 3-7 Jan. 2012